Hey, pull!
It's time.
It's gonna be a short stream today.
Because I'm going to jail, actually.
I was finally caught.
It was a good run.
I'm going straight- I'm kidding, I'm not going to jail.
I'm just packing up my shit.
I'm about to move soon.
So yeah, I'm packing.
And I promised myself I would do a lot of that today.
But now I really felt like playing Minecraft, so I'm gonna play a bit of that.
I made myself some tea, just to calm down after the- The prison incident.
It's okay, though.
It is black tea with forest fruit or something.
I don't know.
I'm not a tea expert.
I put some honey in there.
Yes, many crimes have been committed.
How short?
Probably 42 minutes.
Plus, minus... I don't know.
Two hours.
Something like that.
I'm just saying it's not going to be like a crazy long stream.
You're getting 10 ads in a row?
Good.
That's 10 times more money for me.
When do we get a webcam?
When I hit a million subscribers on YouTube.
I've been saying this ever since I was at 3k subscribers.
And I'm still holding...
Or considering that a thing I will do if I get to a million.
Yeah.
I don't think it'll ever happen, so...
Maybe.
I like the Oliver voice only.
Thank you.
Yeah, trust me.
You don't want to see me.
It's gonna... it's gonna subtract...
from the overall experience.
Seeing my mug.
And then I can't sit here all like a slob anymore, you know?
I gotta...
Well, I don't gotta, but I could.
You know?
Take a shower.
Maybe one day I'll do some webcam stuff.
Hehe.
Hahaha.
What about Jackie cam?
But the thing is...
Listen.
I understand, okay?
Jackie's cute.
She's a cat.
She's awesome.
But I'm not gonna put a Jackie cam obstructing like one-fifth of the screen.
Okay?
It's not gonna happen.
Ever.
Maybe during the breaks I'll figure something out, but...
First I gotta move and figure out something.
I actually have an idea.
So I'm gonna have a bit more space in the new apartment.
So I was thinking of getting another cat bed...
In my gaming room, right?
So that I could potentially...
Have a camera set at the cat during breaks.
Because right now the cat bed is in the living room.
So it's kind of a hassle to...
You know...
Put a cam there.
Yeah, I was thinking about that roughene, huh?
I had an idea of...
If you spun it enough...
Or fast enough that there would be a food dispenser...
It dispensed snacks for Jackie.
But it's just an idea at this point.
I haven't taken any steps to actually make it happen.
Be aware of Windows when streaming with a cam?
What do you mean?
What's going on with Windows?
To a blind playthrough of real life?
That's what I'm doing right now.
It's just not being streamed anywhere.
I'm playing life off stream.
Okay.
I think that teabag is good.
Shrimp Prophet.
I am indeed a liar.
I lie all the time.
And I can't stop lying.
It's just how I am, man.
I was born dishonest.
Okay.
Let's just get going.
I'm actually a...
Like...
A huge liar, you know?
I can't stop lying.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa.
I just had a black screen flicker.
We gotta turn off the thingy.
I almost forgot.
Here we go.
We're back.
Oh, oh, oh.
Okay, there we are.
It's working.
Ah, man.
What a house.
What a beautiful house.
What an absolutely amazing thing I did last time.
But...
I'm not done.
I am gonna relax so hard today, guys.
I'm gonna drink my tea.
I'm gonna detail my house.
I'm gonna sit on the porch.
Read the newspaper like I said I would.
And take in the sun.
That's the plan.
Because now I got a shit ton of cobblestone.
You know what that means.
We gotta do the outside.
I wanna fix this side here.
Because this is not...
...pleasing me.
It's making me unhappy.
Man, the digging last time was nuts.
I don't think I've even begun to fathom...
...the possibilities that I now have, you know?
With the digging.
It's going to be next level.
Only my imagination is the limit now.
Ah!
Whoa!
He came up right next to me!
That bastard!
Fuck me!
Tell me that wasn't designed to be a fucking jump scare!
Right off the bat as well?
Like, what is going on?
Christ on a bike!
I cannot throw anything away.
Maybe the lever.
No.
I can't throw it away.
I gotta go stash it.
Ah, that's full.
You know what?
This exotic chest is now non-exotic.
No, it's not.
We're gonna make another chest.
Let's not start getting sloppy here.
When you get sloppy, that's when things go downhill.
Uh...
I need to make another chest.
We're not done.
Chest.
I'm just gonna put this here.
I mean, ideally, we're gonna have chests everywhere here.
Um...
We're gonna have chests there and there.
Yeah, it's gonna be good.
Right.
Let's put this in here.
Where's my redstone stuff?
Ah, this is the one now.
So let's just...
Pour some stuff in here.
Good.
Let's go grab that pearl before it disappear-o.
Robert De Niro.
Dude, I started watching The Nick.
Like, I watched a couple episodes a long time ago.
Didn't really get into it.
Now I started watching it with a friend.
And we're three episodes deep.
And it's amazing.
Highly recommend The Nick.
The Nick-a-bocker.
Um...
I need to grab the planks.
No, not the planks.
I need stripped wood.
I don't know why I just thought of that.
It's because of Robert De Niro.
He's in that, you know?
The main character.
That's why I thought of it.
And that was a lie.
See?
This is what I mean.
I can't stop lying.
I lie all the time.
It's too much fun.
Even, like, ordinary things, you know?
People will stop me on the street.
Uh, excuse me, sir.
Do you have the time?
And it's like 3.30 and I'll be like, Yeah, it's 1.20.
You know?
And I lie about it.
And then I...
I, you know, I...
I receive happiness.
From knowing that they're gonna walk around knowing that the time is wrong.
See, that was also a lie.
I don't actually do that.
I can't stop!
Oh my goodness.
I have a problem.
You will never be able to know anything for certain anymore.
Why is that so funny?
Why is lying so fun, you know?
It's weird, man.
Obviously, I realize that we're not gonna have full cobblestone.
It's gonna look like crap.
So we're gonna have to detail it with some, you know, variations here and there.
It's gonna look good.
You'll see.
It's gonna be just like I did to my house in that other season.
I mean, already it doesn't look too bad, honestly.
I like it.
I do.
Now I just need to figure out how to make the mossy variant.
Can I make it?
I can make carpets.
I don't wanna make the carpets.
I wanna make mossy stones.
Wait, let me think.
Moss is...
Moss grows on...
rocks.
It, it, uh...
We can maybe find it in caves or maybe in the water.
I've had it before.
I remember how to do it, maybe.
Um...
For now, though, let me see.
Do I need to make anything else stone?
Yeah, maybe this wall as well, actually.
Better start using the stone I have, you know?
Yeah, we're gonna have to fix those, uh...
My OCD here is...
Annoying me.
Dark oak.
It's just pretend OCD.
It's not real.
See?
I lied again.
I lied about having OCD.
Wait, didn't I have a door here?
Yeah.
And I did that, that, that.
Nice!
That looks good, man!
But I'm not gonna do every wall stone.
We're gonna mix it up a little, so, you know, we have stone here.
Uh, this is gonna be stone as well.
I will stop applying stone at some point.
Excuse me.
You can trust me on that.
I know when to stop.
But, uh...
The house was definitely a little too brown.
I knew it at the time.
I know it now.
Everyone knows it.
That's why I'm applying some stone.
Um, I should...
You know what?
I should always wear one of those handlebars.
Just so I can get up anywhere I want.
There we go.
Let me see.
Dude, that is looking...
Prim and proper.
Big fan of that.
Obviously, we're gonna have stone here in the garden as well.
I'm actually not a big fan of what I did here last time.
I may tear this down.
And, uh...
Well, not tear it all down.
I'm gonna change it a little bit, you know?
And obviously, we're gonna see the stone on this side.
But you know what?
It's part of the charm.
Like I said...
It's supposed to look a little ramshackle, you know?
It's the charm behind it.
Um...
We're doing good on food.
It's soon time for the andesite casing revolution.
But not yet.
It shall happen at some point.
I may also put a sign on these chests so I don't keep getting confused about it.
Because I am indeed confused.
About it.
This doesn't belong there.
This belongs in here.
For some reason.
Started raining.
I'm gonna go to bed.
Cheers.
Mmm.
Oh my god.
Here we go again.
Oi!
What's up, my friend?
Come to me!
Brought some grass for me.
Oh, another pearl.
Thank you.
That's actually one more for the collection.
Elytra soon.
In fact, I kind of want to just go collect items from the end.
As well, just to see if there's anything new that pops up that I can make.
You know?
I'm sure there are.
Now, this was stone.
Do I need to make anything else stone?
Let me think.
So we have this wall now.
That looks nice.
That looks really nice.
Um, I think I'll leave these as wood.
Yeah.
Maybe this one will be stone?
Because it's technically, you know...
Yeah, actually, yes.
That's stone.
Definitely stone.
Let me grab the handlebar.
Wait, where is it?
Did I leave it here?
Handlebar?
Where are you, buddy?
There you are.
Let's just leave that...
It looks like a telephone to me.
Yes, this is dog.
Up we go.
And we remove all this.
And I think I just got rid of all my stone, so I gotta go grab it again.
Why is there stone here?
Oh, right.
Okay, actually, that makes sense.
It just looks weird.
Doesn't look right, does it?
Man, this looks...
It's okay.
It's gonna be covered up.
It's fine.
Don't worry about it.
God, I love that thing.
What a feeling.
Dup, dup, dup, dup, dup.
Do I like it?
Let me think.
Let me see from downstairs.
Oh, you know what?
Let's do this wall, too.
I promise I'll stop after this one.
It's the last wall we're doing stone.
No more walls after this one.
Just to mix it with that.
You know, make it fit.
Hells, yeah.
And he saw that it was great.
Okay, no more.
We're done.
No more stone.
Right?
Let me just double check.
Maybe on this side, actually, a little bit.
Yeah, this part here needs to match...
This is the last one.
It's symmetry.
You see this?
It has to be.
Are we good?
No, not yet.
Ah, wait.
What's this?
That ain't right.
Put that there.
Hold on.
My phone is making noises.
Oh, I just had some grass!
I guess from the Enderman.
Thank you, Enderman.
I'm not done with the dirt yet.
We're gonna dirt it up even more.
Soon.
For now, I think I'm happy.
And then...
Ooh, this looks kinda weird, though.
I don't like that.
Wait, hold on.
Okay, this wall also becomes stone.
That's the last one.
But for real, last, last.
Oh, no.
Put that back.
I don't even have stone, for some reason.
I used it all.
Yeah!
I'm happy, I think.
I'm okay.
It looks okay.
Use the axe here.
And then use this.
There we go.
Same here.
Hell yeah.
Obviously, these need to move.
I have Silk Touch.
I could do it now.
But where do I wanna put them?
Hmm.
I'm not sure.
Oh!
I put stakes on the table.
It was unintentional.
Okay.
We got clipboards.
Let's just apply those real fast, so we don't forget.
In fact, one of them I have to bring with me, I believe.
Let me see.
This one is...
Look.
Oh, this is the one I need to carry around.
So this is the one that goes here.
Yep.
Good.
Clipboard.
We don't need this anymore.
We can just delete that.
This we also have on the control.
Coal we don't need anymore.
Diamonds we definitely need.
Andesite we need.
Look for swamp.
Why is that?
Oh!
Because I wanted to find the green gloop.
But now that we have it, who cares?
Kill Enderman is still on the docket.
Yep.
Maybe I'll put that in my toolbox.
If I can find it.
Oh, there's a bow in here.
I would never have found this bow, by the way, if I didn't just see it now.
I'm glad I just saw it.
There's my toolbox.
And this inventory is a disgrace.
Let's fix it.
I think I'm pretty much done with the house for now.
What's happening there?
Well, obviously we're not done, but for now.
I need to put in paths and all that stuff, you know?
I need different types of bricks here.
Speak enough, we should totally cook some of those.
There we go.
More cobblestone.
Now, wait a minute.
I should probably set up the fan situation first.
It's going to be better in the long run.
But I would need a hopper for that.
I think I have a hopper somewhere.
Didn't I have one?
It's not there.
Give me this.
Oh, man.
What a mess this is.
Fix the inventory.
Oh, glass bottles here?
That ain't right.
One chicken.
We also need one arrow on us, of course.
Torches go there.
I like the sound of the spinning machinery in the background.
It's actually kind of calming.
Really dig that.
Okay.
These are just blocks in here.
Now, I had a fan, didn't I?
Is it still outside?
It may still be outside.
There it is.
So, I need to check something here.
Fan.
Smoking, blasting, haunting.
This is food, obviously.
It is blasting that we want to do.
Yeah.
We just pour in a shit ton of cobblestone and blast it into stone.
But we need a hopper for this so I don't jump in and die when trying to collect the items.
This is the big deal.
So, we got to set up something robust here.
The infrastructure demands it.
Let me just see.
I must have a hopper somewhere.
Not in here.
Oh, wait.
Is it maybe back at the digging machine?
No, it's on my freaking corpse.
I was about to say.
Redstone dust goes in the other bucket over here.
Same as that.
Maybe I can go collect some honey, actually.
Are you ready for me?
You're not ready for me.
You know what?
The good thing is I think I can hear it when it's ready.
Because they go...
You know, like bees do.
So, I just wait for that sound.
And as soon as I hear it, then I know it's time.
Put all this stuff in there.
Maybe not the rails.
This one.
Superglue?
I think that's about it.
I can't stack these, unfortunately.
Maybe they go in...
Nah, put them in here.
It's fine.
No, that's breaking the rule.
Don't break the rule.
Put them here.
Bucket stays on me.
What about my rails?
Let's put these in here, then.
To make them in the same one with the rails here.
The lever is definitely also...
I need a...
Yeah, I need to figure this out, man.
This is nuts.
Hold on.
Let me make a shit ton of chests.
Let's get this one over with.
23 chests.
Oh, I need more.
Damn!
I thought that was more than enough.
26 chests.
Look at that.
Isn't that wonderful?
Now we put in some lights.
Maybe here.
Or even...
Here.
Let me put one here as well.
Oh, I could also use lanterns, actually.
Hold on.
Lanterns.
Iron nuggets.
That's a much better idea.
Eight lanterns.
Oh!
We can smoke the lantern!
I like it!
Okay, check this out.
I have an idea.
We are gonna...
I'm gonna be a little, uh...
Modern...
With my artistic vision here.
Okay, check this out.
Let me see.
This is great.
We're gonna make a tiny, like...
Modern art installation here.
Oh, shit.
Okay.
No, wait.
Let's do, like...
Here.
Slaps!
Slap me.
Boom!
Look at that!
What do you think?
Huh?
Pretty good!
Maybe one more?
Actually...
Let's go three.
Look at that modern shit, dude!
Mmm...
Not bad!
Give me these meats.
Thank you.
It's a little weird, the way that works.
But I'm happy.
Oh, hell yeah.
That just did so much.
Trapdoors.
Nuggets.
Nug me.
Oh, stack the steak.
So, we have the hopper now.
Then we need lava, which we have right here.
I can grab that.
It's no biggie.
Oh!
There we go.
I got it.
So, lava, we have a fan.
And we have hopper.
But then we also need a chest, right?
And the best way to do this...
Let me actually think about this.
Hopefully, the lava is not going to flow through the hopper.
I don't think that's a thing.
But who knows with this mod, right?
Can't be too sure.
Let me see here.
So, the fan...
It's just a rod and the pooper.
Easy.
So, I can grab that from pretty much anywhere.
I could do it over here, but...
Do I want to do it there?
Maybe not.
I mean, I could do it.
Actually, it's...
Yeah, it's fine.
Let's just do it here.
Oh, the other way...
Wait, is it sucking in?
Wait, can I change the...
Configuration on that?
Wait, for some reason, it's...
It needs to spin the other way.
Oh, interesting.
So, that's how that works.
Now it's blowing.
Before, it was sucking.
Why can't I jump out of here when this thing is on?
That is so weird.
Oh.
Again?
What is it with the Enderman today?
Hey.
Come at me.
Uh-oh.
Where are you?
Oh.
Oh, shit.
Oh!
Oh, my God.
I'm dying!
I'm okay.
Holy shit.
Stand still!
Another pearl for me.
Wow.
Dude, I'm not even doing anything, and I'm winning.
Feels good, yo.
Wait, how do we get a rail?
Oh, I picked it up.
Put it in there.
Okay, let's continue the shenanigans over here.
So, we're gonna put lava here.
This is where the items go, which means...
We're gonna have a chest down here.
Uh, the other way.
Not that it matters, I guess.
We're gonna have a hopper.
It's gonna point at the chest.
Like that.
Lava there.
Uh, but is that not gonna flow in there?
Wait.
Let me think.
Also, we need to cover this up.
Make a little entrance hatch here.
We can see the chest.
There we go, we go...
Oh, wait.
I can't.
Uh, we need a, um...
We need a slab or something.
Maybe I can use these.
Let me see if that works.
Let's try lava.
Uh, oh.
So...
Yeah, okay.
That's a problem.
Let me try this, then.
Looking good!
But now I need a way to deposit items.
Oh!
Flapjack!
We're gonna flap that.
Where's my flapjack set?
There's one.
I don't need 41.
I need one.
I probably take this before I do this.
Just to play it safe.
So let me go like that.
Whenever we want to deposit.
Huh?
Not bad, huh?
Actually.
I'm going to do...
This way.
Oh, shit.
Oh, no.
Oh.
Fuck.
Fuck off.
Wait, it's not gonna burn my flapjack, is it?
I'm kind of worried about this lava.
Please don't burn my shit.
No!
Oh, I removed lava.
Oh, I'm stuck again.
God damn it.
Okay, we gotta go get more.
I was trying to cover the top, so if it spouted in every direction, it wouldn't spout, you know?
Don't like it when it spouts up.
Like that.
Or spits.
Whatever the word is.
Okay.
I guess I could simply put it here.
Hey, actually.
Hey, look at that!
That works.
Not bad!
Open!
You ready?
What am I cooking?
Oh, let me go get something to cook.
Let's cook some stone.
And dude, it's gonna cook all of it simultaneously or what?
Or is it...
Let's see.
Maybe it's gonna do it one by one.
Probably not, right?
Wait a second.
Oh, oh, oh, wait, wait.
I see a problem.
We need redstone.
I saw the problem before we started.
I saw the problem.
We can try...
I mean, there's different ways to do this, I guess.
We also have a chute.
Let me actually see what that was.
Transport items vertically.
Yes.
But there's something about a filter, right?
Using the wrench, a window can be created.
Right.
We can connect.
Connect them.
Using encased fans at the top or bottom, a chute can move items upward.
Dude, that in itself is actually kind of mind-blowing right now.
That you can do that.
Smart chutes or vertical chutes with additional control.
I think this is the one.
Items in the filter slot.
Ah.
Ah, but wait a minute.
I don't want to do that.
No.
My solution is better.
Have a better one.
Red.
This one.
No, I'll leave her.
Let me see.
I have to remember exactly how this works with the dang hoppers.
It is a little weird with the hoppers.
But I think it's like here?
Now I put an item in?
Let me put some of this.
Wait, why not be cooking?
It's not blasting anything.
Hold on, is that because of the... Oh, shit.
Uh-oh.
Wait, was it getting... I'm actually so confused.
You know, we can just move it one over.
Who cares?
Let's just make a little bit more room here.
Like this.
Oh, the other way.
Oh, God.
Oh, my God.
Okay, now.
Here.
We're gonna put... Let me think.
Lava here.
Flapjack here.
Let me actually see if this even works.
I need to figure out how this actually works before I start doing anything.
So let me get rid of this.
Oh, God.
Oh, don't cover that.
Right.
So let's put in lava.
Okay, that works, right?
So now...
Yeah, it's blasting.
You can see the smoke.
Oh, is it?
Yeah, it is.
It is.
Right?
Yeah.
Yeah, look!
Amazing.
So now...
Uh... Let me think.
Yeah.
That's it.
That's it, I think.
We have done it.
Hopper.
Okay.
And now we go in here.
Lever.
Boom.
Wait, what?
Wait a minute.
I think this one is getting cooked.
This one is not.
Because it's like...
Further down.
Yeah.
Look.
Okay.
And then I go here.
And do that.
And then... Okay.
Hmm.
I mean, that's fine.
I guess I can just do this.
Oh, shit.
Oh, I can't open it.
Oh, wait.
Hold on.
I guess this is fine like this as well.
Don't need to cover it up.
I'll simply go like this now.
Ah, shit!
Stop.
Ah.
Gimme.
There we go.
Arrested.
Boom.
It's in the corner.
It works.
And now, watch.
As soon as it's ready.
Wait, can I not just walk over and grab it?
Oh!
It's burning!
Oh.
Fuck.
Oh, no.
Stop.
Jesus.
Oh, crap.
Yeah, well.
Okay, then.
I mean, I'm trying to do it half-hearted, you know?
I need to really do this.
And I'm not doing it.
I'm just sort of trying to take a shortcut here, you know?
It's not the right way to do it.
We're gonna abandon this idea for now.
Now, I will revisit this in the future.
I can't think about this right now.
It's too much.
Go to bed.
Drink my tea.
Go in here now.
I mean, it's definitely totally worth investigating and making this work.
Now, you could do it, obviously, with the filter.
And it's gonna work wonders, right?
I'm just too lazy.
I wanna set something out that works for everything immediately.
So, yeah.
This doesn't go there.
God, I can't stand opening these chests left and right.
I need signs on them.
We gotta make signs right now.
Before I lose my damn mind.
We have some.
Sticks.
There we go.
Now, boom.
This...
Is...
Create.
Let me put it in the center.
This...
Is...
Uh...
Smelting?
Stone.
And...
Wood.
No.
It is wood.
The other one is stone.
Yeah!
God.
Oh.
Oof.
Wood.
Stone.
Bring all the stone.
That's not stone.
This is stone.
That's stone.
Scanning.
Stone.
Bring it in there.
Yes.
That's also stone in my book.
This is exotic.
Doesn't belong there.
Stone.
Tiny stones.
Technically.
That's exotic.
All that would go in here.
And then over here.
This one is...
You guessed it!
Miscellaneous.
Miscellanois.
Use.
Miscellaneous.
There we go.
Actually, there's two L's in this word.
Miscell...
And there's only one N, I believe.
Miscellaneous.
That is correct.
Uh...
Signs.
I guess we can put the signs...
This is exotic.
These are temporary names.
We will further granularize later.
This is exotic.
What was this one or that one?
Where's my...
Oh, we need a chest for...
This is going to be the chest...
For...
Equipment.
Put it all in there.
The bed is equipment.
So is this.
And that.
Yep.
Dude, the wrench actually seems kind of...
Big, you know?
I feel like I should always carry that around.
We need a redstone.
N.
Do I have more redstone stuff?
I do have a couple things.
Lantern.
That is, um...
We're going to have a construction.
That's lanterns.
Actually, I kind of want to put these lanterns all over.
Oh, hells yeah.
Oh!
Dude, even here.
Nice!
Oh!
That's going to do so much.
Very good.
Okay, this is looking hella nice.
The only thing I don't like about these signs...
Is that they're very dark.
Meaning the text is harder to read.
You know, if I use oak signs...
It's much easier to read.
It's on the docket.
It's on the to-do list.
It's not.
But it will be.
In a second here.
Uh, you know what we should have?
We should have another clipboard.
Alloy, paper, plank.
That would be...
Alloy.
Paper would be miscellaneous.
Plank would be wood.
Oh, look at this.
The system is already working.
This is going to be...
This is the construction checklist.
We want...
No.
Let me think here.
Change signs to oak.
Put down...
A...
Stone...
Walkway.
What else do we need to do around the house?
These are chores.
Um...
Create...
A...
Proper...
Fan...
Setup.
Yes.
Relocate...
Windmill...
To proper...
Location.
Because I don't like where it is right now.
All that is temporary, right?
Create big factory.
With belts.
We're gonna...
Uh...
Yeah, that's about it for now, I guess.
No.
Uh, find flowers...
And decorate.
We're also gonna...
Detail...
The stone works...
With moss...
And crack...
Cocaine.
No!
Just crack stones.
Crack stones.
That's it for now.
Put it here.
This is the checklist for construction.
All right.
Good stuff.
Uh, we kinda need some food here.
Let's go feed the animals.
They want wheat and they want seeds.
Oh, that's something else.
We shall have...
Uh, proper big...
Grazing country...
For animals.
With proper...
Enclosures.
Very nice.
What's up, cows?
I brought food for y'all.
It's been a while.
I know you've been starving.
It's okay.
Don't worry.
It's fine.
Everyone gets to eat.
Everyone eats.
Now, chickens I got for you too.
Good.
Everyone ate?
Nobody going hungry?
Okay, then.
Keep it up.
Wait, should I make that stone too?
Hmm.
No, no, no.
We're done with stone.
Ah, okay.
Planks.
Oh, uh, this one belongs in construction.
What else belongs in construction?
Stuff like that.
And this.
And that.
That one too.
This one.
This is only wood.
This is redstone.
Okay.
Pumpkins are fragile, apparently.
Doors.
Wool.
I don't know about wool.
It's definitely not wood, right?
Limestone is stone.
Sand is also stone, technically.
Put those in there.
Now, white wool for now is going to be miscellaneous.
We obviously need a food chest as well.
This is construction too.
Spectral arrows is equipment.
Let's put consumable stuff down in the bottom right.
Or like, you know, something a little more loose.
Like, these things are loose.
Well, everything's kind of loose now that I think about it.
This is equipment up here.
This is weapons and usables.
You know what I mean?
Pretty good.
Okay.
I think I want to go to see if I can find some moss.
Actually.
And we also want to keep enchanting things.
Maybe I'll see what's next on the enchantment.
I have a...
Pig axe.
Apparently.
Somehow I have a full-blown pig axe ready.
Efficiency 3.
That's just...
Terrible.
No thank you.
What about axe?
Also efficiency 3.
Why is that?
Hmm.
That's fine though.
Put that in there.
That one too.
Oh, I don't have any boots on.
Also, I don't want to be wearing these goggles actually.
Not right now.
I'd rather be protected.
There we go.
Fully diamond.
Yo, I should go get the nether armor.
Netherite armor.
Oh, wait.
We're gonna bring the digging machine to the nether.
Yo, that's the way to...
We're gonna make a 100 by 100 square meter digging machine.
And I will systematically destroy the nether.
And you know what else?
I'm gonna make a protective bubble around the digging machine consisting of...
Oblivion.
Obsidian.
So that lava cannot get to it.
Think about that.
Is that smart or what?
Oh, dude!
Oh, man.
Oh, that's just another application of the digging machine.
There are so many.
It's crazy.
Oh, my God.
Okay.
I don't know what to do first.
Maybe we work on...
I wanna go explore, man.
It's been a while.
I need to go find that hotel.
Because I kinda wanna steal it.
Last time I went north.
Let's go south.
And I also wanna find the mossy stuff.
So we can get ready to...
Do the things around the house.
And also potentially make the factory.
To make the factory, I guess we would need a lot of stone.
It needs to be like a stone building, right?
It needs to look industrial.
In fact, what can I make that's kinda stony?
Maybe over here.
Block of...
Oh, that's way too expensive.
Probably looks cool.
Block of brass.
Also way too expensive.
Copper casing.
Did I even try that?
Oh, we're gonna have pipes in the factory as well.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, right.
Elevator.
Wait, where should the elevator be?
I actually totally forgot that there was a hole beneath this floor.
Dude.
What if I click a button?
This entire section?
An elevator below it.
Or we hoist it up.
No, wait, hold on.
Let me think.
Wait, how do I even...
How would I even do that?
That sounds crazy.
I guess I would have to rotate it somehow and then...
Wait.
How's that even gonna work?
Huh.
Dude, I have an idea.
Oh, I have the craziest idea, guys.
Okay.
We're doing this.
Right now.
This is a bigger project, okay?
But this is gonna be insane.
I don't...
I don't think you understand how crazy my idea is.
Okay?
Let me...
I actually have such a smile on my face right now.
Let me see here.
We definitely need rope pulleys.
Wool, sheets, and casing.
I got it.
Wool.
Sheets.
Oh, wait.
Uh, I need more iron sheets.
Let's go press some.
Yeah!
You're doing that?
Great.
And while that's pressing...
I'm gonna get the last thing I needed, which was...
So, we had wool, iron sheets, and casing.
Right.
We got eight of those.
Okay.
I also had one of these.
Let me go grab some of them right now.
So, I guess I only need, like, four.
Or...
Maybe more, actually.
It depends how this works.
Also, I need to check something.
Oh, yeah.
There's, uh, two layers.
Just had to confirm.
Whew!
Uh...
Okay!
Wait, wait, wait.
I need to see something.
Ah, okay.
Hmm.
Okay.
Maybe...
Maybe not, then.
A little questionable now.
Okay.
Basically, my idea was that the entire floor here was gonna be hoisted down.
Like, the entire floor going...
You know?
But the cave is not big enough.
Unfortunately.
But imagine...
I guess I could make the cave bigger.
Man.
Let's just...
How about we start simple?
Just to see...
Proof of concept, you know?
I guess I can do, like, the middle section here only.
For now.
Let me try and make these things...
Pull.
Wait, I need to see this again.
Show me the elevator thing.
Here we go.
Oh, wait.
We're gonna have to connect all these, of course.
No?
Only one of them was enough, right?
Something like that.
Connect the structure.
Right.
Wait.
Okay.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Good.
Okay.
So, that seems simple enough, doesn't it?
What was it?
Pulley?
One, two, three, four.
Can't be that easy.
Is that angled correctly?
I guess it is.
Wait.
That's...
Okay.
I guess we need rope.
Rope coupling.
Oh, do I need this down there?
No, I guess I...
Wait.
Hold on.
I have a rope somewhere.
Always place when stopped.
Place only in starting position.
Place only when anchored...
I don't know what that means.
How come I can't connect this?
I need to see the rope.
Right-clicking a rope winch and connector with a rope coupling will attach them.
When given rotational force, rope winch is real in and...
Okay.
But how the fuck do I connect the thingies?
How is it connected here?
Oh, let me see.
Oh, the rope is inside of it already.
I see.
Okay.
Okay, so that means...
We just gotta crank it, actually.
That's all that means.
Wait.
Oh, that's funny.
Oh, that's weird.
Oh, no, no, no.
The other way.
Okay.
We need...
I was about to say lemonade.
Super glue.
Why did I say lemonade?
But we have a double layer, so we need to be careful here.
How am I gonna do this?
I guess I can...
I have an idea.
I almost fell down.
Wait, did I do it?
Selected blocks must be connected.
But they are connected.
What do you mean?
Oh, wait.
I need one here, I guess.
Oh.
Oh, I can't take these with me?
Wait, maybe I need to, um...
Pull this up first.
Oh, no.
Give me this.
One higher, please.
I mean, I guess I can do that.
But how do I then...
Oh, wait.
I know.
Just do this.
But they're not connected now, are they?
No, they're not.
There we go.
But then these...
Can I not just make it neat?
Brother!
Is that it?
There we go.
We got it, I think.
Okay, you ready?
Here we go.
Where's my crank?
Oh, it's there.
Oh, okay!
Okay, you know what?
Let's get rid of that bottom part, I guess.
Fuck it.
I can't be bothered to figure out how the fuck this works.
With the bottom part.
So, one, two, three, four.
One, two, three, four.
No, one, two, three.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Oh, no.
It's not even...
Ah.
Brother.
God damn it.
There's not even room.
I just assumed that would be.
miscalculated.
Let's try somewhere else.
I just want to see if this actually works.
That works.
Okay.
So, we know it works.
Now, we're just going to figure out a way to do it in a nice way here.
Maybe we have an elevator room in that case.
Where should it be?
I could tear down a wall, maybe, and do it in between.
How can I look good?
I put a wall along here.
That's awkward, man.
Man, I don't like what I've done here.
Okay.
I'm actually gonna...
Yeah.
I've decided.
I'm making a fucking hole here.
It's happening.
I will not let the natural world ruin my dreams.
I will actually destroy all of this.
I have a dream.
Oh, no!
And I need to realize it, you know?
You must understand.
Wait, what?
Oh, it's because I'm using Silk Touch.
I'm getting new blocks, technically.
Yeah, and this is actually perfect.
We can even do one more layer here, but...
We'll see how it goes.
I can't believe I'm actually making an elevator.
And it's gonna work.
Obviously, we gotta wire it up.
So it can run automatically, so I don't have to crank that shit every time.
But it's cool to know that I could crank it.
Where are you?
Are you...
Oh, you're right there.
Sounded like he was behind the wall here.
I guess it is kind of cool coming down and then being in the corner.
Oh, we're not even going all the way down.
Hold on.
Wait a minute.
I need to check something.
I would love to be, like...
Pulled down into the center of the big cave, you know?
Let me see what the situation is.
Yo, what if...
Dude.
Oh my god.
Yo.
Wait.
I have a great idea.
Oh.
Guys, you're gonna love this.
I am smiling so much just thinking about it.
Oh, this is sick.
This is so sick.
It's actually fine that we're only going here.
This is great.
I'm not gonna reveal what the idea is because it's so funny.
And, you know what?
I'm almost certain it's gonna work, too.
Like, I'm not 100%, but I'm pretty 100%, you know?
Like, almost 100%.
I'm, like, 98.2.
First, we gotta dig this.
Let me see.
Then we need a little platform here.
We may not be able to have these torches on the wall, actually.
I don't know how that's gonna work.
That's gonna mess it up, right?
Or maybe not, actually, since it's animated.
They do kind of ignore all the blocks on the way, don't they?
I think it's fine.
I need to see exactly how that...
I need to go further down, actually.
I want you to think of those sports that people do.
Okay?
Think of the sports people do when they go out and they swim.
And when they're done swimming, they jump on a bike.
When they're done biking, they start running.
Okay?
This is what I need you to be thinking about right now.
Put a light there.
Okay, let's try it, man!
What's the best way up?
Maybe here.
Did I do this correctly, then?
Let me see.
I would put it here.
Yeah, I think so.
We're gonna crank it at first, just to test.
This is just a preliminary test.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
We need to connect these with.
Oh, it's already connected.
Oh, my God.
Amazing.
Okay, so it should just work.
It should just work, right?
Here we go, here we go.
Oh, no!
Okay, fuck this thing.
We don't care.
Yo, this is sick!
Wait, wait, wait.
I can make it better.
Wheel me.
I need a gearbox.
Gearbox!
Watch this.
I'm gonna grab this.
I'm gonna bring it over here.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Why?
Are you not a vertical gearbox?
You're not!
Make it vertical!
I guess we don't need the wheel.
I just want to have an easier access here while I'm standing on the platform.
Oh, wait a minute, I...
I see the problem.
Uh, yeah.
Yep.
Hold on.
We have a problem.
I guess I...
Hmm.
Yep.
That's a thing.
So, wait, so even if I activate...
Let's say I activate...
It's activated, right?
And it's...
And we go...
What then?
I'm down?
What do I do?
How do I...
How do I even get back up?
I guess I would have to have a remote connection that I click...
And then it somehow reverses direction or something.
Yeah.
Hold on.
This is all cool.
This is cool and all.
But we need to fix something more basic first.
We have some issues here.
Okay?
Bring it back up.
There we go.
I need to do some pretty basic experiments here.
Give me this.
Give me that.
Okay.
For sure there's a way to reverse...
Direction with redstone or something, right?
I feel like I've read about that here.
In some of these components.
Maybe even the analog lever, actually.
Let me see what that said.
There's something about reversing here.
Compact and precise source of redstone power.
Yes.
Right-click to increase its analog power output.
Yeah?
Right-click while sneaking to decrease it.
Okay.
Oh, that's not actually reversing anything.
Let me think.
Maybe something more basic.
Yes.
Brass or andesite casing can be used to decorate them.
Components added after encasing will not connect to the shaft outputs.
Oh, interesting.
I guess that...
No, that doesn't make sense.
After encasing.
Oh, you gotta use a wrench on that.
Ah.
Okay.
Well, that's not exactly what I was looking for.
Ah, let me think.
It's probably related to windmills and stuff, actually, now that I think about it.
Because windmills produce power, right?
Ah, but I don't want to disassemble that.
Windmills or water mills?
Do I have any of that?
Maybe the mechanical bearing, actually?
Let me see that one.
It's actually the block in front of them.
Yes.
Oh, here we go.
Watch this.
When stopped, the bearing will place the structure at the nearest grid-aligned angle.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
I need to see this.
Maybe we can modify it.
Okay, it's not that one.
Ah, let's just experiment with some redstone, then.
Because there's 100% the way to do this.
It is the most obvious thing you can do, right?
Let's see what happens when I apply redstone to various things.
This doesn't even make sense, what I'm trying to do.
This doesn't make any sense at all.
Wait, analog lever.
Let me see this again.
It didn't say something about reverse, right?
It just said decrease and increase.
Yeah, decrease.
Brother.
Let me see here.
Kinetic sources.
Windmill bearing.
Attached to the block in front of them.
Is there something about redstone here?
Okay.
No, it's got to be like a little component, right?
Logic components.
Throttle lever.
Make for a compact and precise source of redstone power.
Right click and drag to set its analog power output.
Using a wrench, the signal can be inverted?
I don't know what that means when it comes to redstone.
What does it mean, inverting a signal?
That makes no sense to me, actually.
Okay, so we pulled in this direction.
Power goes that way.
And it's right here now, because it's set in this position.
Using a wrench, the signal can be inverted.
Oh, it simply means that you can now increase power in the other direction, I guess.
That's what that means.
It doesn't mean there's such a thing as an inverted signal.
I mean, I guess there is a way where we can maybe...
Use a piston to move a block into position to spin the other way.
But I feel like that's way overcomplicating something that should be kind of easy to do.
You know what I mean?
This is way overthinking it.
Let's say I have a shaft.
Let's just say I have an infinitely long shaft.
And at various points on the shaft, I have this thing I can rotate.
So that wherever I am, I can rotate it.
Or, hold on.
When this thing comes to the bottom, I have a separate source of power.
That simply is reversed.
So that when it's in position, it is already aligned.
Ah, but wait a minute.
That doesn't even make any sense.
It needs to stay up here, of course.
Fuck.
Turning it that way.
Huh?
Oh, no!
Did I break it?
What have I done?
What's wrong with it?
Oh.
Okay, there we go.
We're back.
Whew!
I thought I broke the whole thing.
Dude, I...
I need to figure this out.
There's no way.
What can I use?
Gearshift?
Shifting gear sounds proper.
Wait.
Uh...
Gearshift.
I have no idea what that does, but we can try it.
Cogwheel and decide.
And decide?
And decide.
Cogwheel we have?
I don't have enough, though.
Wood and shaft.
Make me some.
Uh, what was I making?
Oh, yeah.
Gear.
Wait.
Sequenced gear shift.
Oh, redstone.
Dude, my inventory.
I can't handle it.
I don't want this steak.
Actually, I do.
I'm gonna eat it.
Let's throw away some stuff.
Charcoal is, uh, here.
Okay.
Here we go.
What's this?
Show me it's reversing.
Gear shifts will relay rotation in a straight line.
That's it, baby!
When powered by redstone, it...
Yeah.
Beautiful.
That's it.
Shifting gears.
Unbelievable.
So!
Now we just gotta figure out how to actually use it.
Like that, right?
Then we need some power that needs to go...
Wait, hold on.
I also need...
Actually, I need two buttons, I guess.
Unless I somehow connect it.
So that they're both doing their thing.
Also, something else.
I don't want to have to manually sort of adjust the height every time I go up.
I want it to stop here.
Maybe there's a way to make that happen.
Set, like, a maximum position or something.
You know what I mean?
Like a maximum height that I...
So I don't have to finagle it every time.
Give me a shaft.
I have a shaft.
So let's just say I put a shaft there.
You know, we need to bring it back to basics here.
Give me this.
Let's go outside and have some fun.
We're gonna say, fuck this.
I'm gonna make my own little, uh...
Little engine that could.
Okay?
I need a water wheel.
I didn't make that?
Oh, I guess that was the last world.
Water wheel.
Then we need water.
Water.
Give me water.
You can also go in here.
Now we have that.
So that...
Then we have some rotation going.
I just want to keep things super simple.
Let's make it right here.
I'm gonna do that.
My spade.
Why did I put away my dirt?
You always want to carry around dirt.
One of the best blocks in the game.
There we go.
Good enough.
We got power.
Now we grab it.
Make it simple.
Here.
Look at that rod rotating.
That's beautiful.
Gearshift.
Boom.
Redstone.
Opposite!
Opposite again!
Lovely.
And then...
But that's not the only thing, right?
Basically, I need to pretend that this...
This right here is downstairs.
This is downstairs right here.
And there needs to be a button downstairs.
So we need another button.
Let me just make a...
Or a lever, I guess.
No, make a lever.
That's what I really need.
Stick and cobblestone.
Give me some cobblestone.
Redstone we have.
Okay.
That's downstairs.
I mean, I somehow managed to connect it, right?
I somehow managed to connect that.
Aha!
So we need to use this to override...
When this is on.
So hold on a minute.
This was default, right?
What if I do this now?
Ah, that never reaches it.
True.
Hmm.
Maybe I keep it more simple.
Let's say this is upstairs.
So it's not in the way.
Oh, let me turn that off.
There we go.
Now I turn it on.
Now I go downstairs.
Oh, we definitely need a comparator for this torch.
Quartz stone.
Just one?
I think it was just one.
Also, what's this doing in here?
Torches I don't have.
Oh my god, look at all the new shit!
What the fuck is that?
Whoa!
Okay, dude.
We gotta...
We gotta absolutely explore the redstone.
That's crazy.
Now I need stone.
Dun-dun-dun.
Now I just have to remember exactly how these things work.
Also unlock something new there.
I don't even want to look at it.
Not right now.
That goes that way.
Dude, I totally forgot how this works.
If only I had my redstone book from season two.
That I could read with all my notes.
That turns that on.
Ah, okay.
Okay.
So this just needs to be on at all times.
So let's say I'm upstairs.
And I want to go down.
Boom.
It's going down.
Now I'm downstairs.
Hey!
There it is!
We got it!
Easy.
That's it.
We have made it work.
Now.
We also gotta have a way to pause it though.
We can't just have it go on forever.
That's the problem here.
It needs to stop at the very bottom, right?
Hmm.
So we need to stop the rotation entirely.
How are we gonna do that?
Okay.
So let's say...
Hold on.
So I'm upstairs.
I want to go down.
Oh, wait.
No.
This one needs to be on at all times.
Yeah.
It needs to stop spinning at the start, of course.
Now I could just add another switch in between.
Um...
Right?
That's gonna get messy though.
Just override it with that.
Anyway.
Let's say I'm up here.
I go...
I go down.
Now I'm down.
Now I go up.
And I'm upstairs.
Ah!
It only works once.
I see the problem.
Yikes.
Let me actually just take a look at all the stuff that I just unlocked.
I just want to see.
I just unlocked a shit ton of things.
Pulse repeater.
What is that?
Threshold switch.
That sounds useful.
Isn't that exactly what a comparator is?
It switches when the threshold is high enough.
Or when a certain power exceeds a threshold.
I guess we can try that.
Pulse extender.
That just sounds like a repeater to me.
But maybe it's a repeater of a pulse specifically.
Which is interesting.
What is sequenced gear shift?
I feel like this may be the answer.
Electron tube.
Polished rose quartz.
And rose quartz was...
Redstone and nether quartz.
This thing?
Sweet.
Iron sheet.
I'm just going to make two of them.
Just to have it.
Cockwheel...
Brass casing.
I guess it's just brass in that one.
Brass sheet.
Do I even have a brass bar?
Brass ingots.
Brass nuggets.
Okay, but how do I...
Wait, how the hell did I make brass?
Oh!
Maybe it was here.
Right!
Okay.
Shit.
That's true.
Zinc, copper.
Zinc and copper.
That one.
And that one.
We also need a power.
Make the guy happy downstairs.
Let's give him some charcoal.
What's up, buddy?
Are you hungry?
Hey?
Look what I got for you!
Eat it!
Yeah.
Now he's happy.
Okay.
Let's throw it in.
Throw it in.
This one and that one.
I'm going to make...
Five.
Mix it up!
That is so satisfying.
It's spinning quite fast, too.
Thanks.
And now we got that.
So all we gotta do...
Is to use this.
And then use this on it, right?
There we go!
Okay.
And with that made...
We can make it.
Sequenced Gearshift.
Now, what the hell is that?
Let's ponder on it.
Sequenced Gearshifts relay rotation by following a timed list of instructions.
Oh!
Oh, no.
It's time-based.
Right-click it to open the configuration UI.
I mean, I could just set a timer of 20 minutes and then be like...
Okay, I'm gonna quick-explore, be back within 20 minutes, or I won't get home.
Upon receiving a redstone signal, it will start running its configured sequence.
Oh!
Interesting.
So I can set it to be like...
Three left, five right, two left.
Like a safe...
Cracking mechanism.
When it's finished, it waits for the next redstone signal and starts over.
Well, this is not exactly what I was looking for.
So let's just keep making things.
I want to make the threshold switch.
Comparator and brass casing.
I have everything except the comparator.
Let's make another comparator.
Which was...
Oh, it's so annoying to make.
I got three stone already.
That's good.
Torches and nether quartz.
Three.
Threshold switch.
Now, what are we dealing with here?
Threshold switches monitor the fill level of containers.
Oh, okay.
Oh, it even has a little UI or a little display on it.
Wait, you can just do that?
You can just put items in the chest like that?
When the inventory content exceeds the upper threshold...
Then something happens.
It sends a redstone signal.
Ah.
That seems very useful in a lot of ways.
That I can't quite see, but I know it's useful.
You know what I mean?
The signal stays until the lower threshold is reached.
You can invert it, I guess.
So as soon as it reaches a certain threshold, then it starts...
sending them out.
The redstone output can now be used to control item supply...
keeping the buffer filled.
Yeah?
Tell me more.
The specific thresholds can be changed in the UI.
You can have both at the same time.
A filter can help to only count specific contents.
Wow.
Man, that's getting some...
That's getting really advanced.
Fluid buffers can be monitored in a similar fashion.
Okay, okay.
Not exactly my tempo, though.
We can also try to make this.
Unless I already made it.
Maybe I should check my stuff here before I make more.
Oh, I have a brass casing in here.
Look!
Neat.
Employer.
Chassis.
Uh...
There, I said it right.
Portable storage interface.
Chassis.
Furnish doesn't belong here.
No, I don't think we made one of these.
Mechanical crafter.
But it doesn't sound like the thing I need right now.
So let's not do that.
Pulse extender.
Hmm.
Clockwork bearing?
Wait, controller rail?
A unidirectional powered rail with variable speed controlled by the signal strength supplied to it.
Okay.
Honey bottle.
What's this?
Redstone inductor?
Damn, son.
Okay.
Copper sheet.
I think we needed this, too.
I didn't quite pay attention.
Redstone inductor.
Let's see that one.
That looks advanced.
Redstone inductors output an analog signal that changes over time to match its input.
What?
Oh, so if there's three in, it's three out?
Seven in.
Seven out.
Nice.
Zero in, zero out.
Okay.
Using the value panel, the rate of change can be configured.
Why would you want something to change slowly, though, and not just have it match immediately?
That's gotta be a reason.
Configured delays can range up to an hour?
Okay.
That's probably something smart you can do with that.
Very interesting.
Who wants to wait an hour?
Smart shoot.
Powered latch.
It doesn't sound like the thing I need.
But who knows?
Honestly, I could probably do all this with comparators, but...
I have to be honest with you.
I don't fucking remember how to use them properly.
It's been so long.
Powered toggle latch.
Small tire.
Pulse timer.
It's gotta be one of these redstone things, though.
What even is a clutch?
Isn't that something that is in a car?
What is that?
Clutches will relay rotation in a straight line.
Okay, what's the...
What's the big woo?
When powered by redstone, it breaks the connection.
Oh, wait a minute.
Isn't this exactly what I need?
I actually forgot what I was looking for, but I needed to stop spinning.
Oh.
Oh, wait a minute.
I just stumbled on the right thing, I think.
I need to see this again, actually.
So when you power it, it stops spinning.
That's it, right?
Wow, that was easy.
Is that what a clutch does?
So wait, you use the clutch in a car and you stop something...
Isn't that a brake?
You stop the wheels from spinning?
I don't know.
I don't know anything about cars.
I don't know shit.
Let me put that here.
Wait, they both...
They both need power at some point, though.
But then that's not going in, I don't think.
Redstone works in mysterious ways in Minecraft, you know?
You need actually a repeater to do this.
Unless they sort of...
Let me put a rod in there.
Huh?
Wait, hold on.
Wait, what is going on?
Am I supposed to be able to type something here?
Wait, now this is on.
Wait, I'm so freaking confused.
I need to see this thing again.
Why did I...
Wait, why do I have so many threshold switches?
What the fuck is going on?
There's a bug?
Game is bugged?
That was weird.
You saw that?
Hold on.
Wait, did I...
Oh, hold on a minute.
Did I put in the wrong thing?
Oh...
Oh my god, bro.
Ha ha!
Wow.
That makes so much sense now.
I was so confused!
Okay, so...
I think we need a...
We need a repeater here.
I'm still stuck in Minecraft mode, you know?
Like, the standard Minecraft.
There's probably a better way of doing it, but whatever.
Stone, redstone, torches.
Let's
make a couple of these.
Also, my inventory is shit!
Oh my god!
I gotta fix it.
Before I lose my damn mind.
White wool.
And then I'll take it when I need it.
That's the plan.
Also, all these weird ones we made, let's just get rid of them.
Sequence the gear shift?
Fuck that!
We don't need it.
Redstone inductor.
Yep.
Okay.
Repeat me.
Did I use all my dust?
Oh no, it's here.
Oh, I may need two of them, actually.
Let me see.
No idea if this is gonna work.
Oops.
Just like that.
Okay, so now they're both on, right?
Which means it's not rotating because this one is on.
And we are still downstairs.
No, we're not downstairs yet.
Oh, we need a comparator, of course.
Here, and then this needs to go...
Let's put it...
Let me actually move this around.
A bit simple.
Okay, so steady state needs to be off.
So I guess...
Let's say this is how it is.
I'm upstairs.
Nothing's moving.
I go...
I wanna go down.
Boom.
Spinning.
We're on the bottom.
That's not gonna do anything because this power is...
Wait, I need to actually invert, I think.
I need to invert signal.
This needs to be on by default.
Crap.
Ah, shit.
Oh, no.
I need the...
I have a torch.
Probably a better way of doing this.
What happens if I just...
Yeah, just one of them turned on.
But, wait a minute.
Hold on.
Just do that.
Ah, wait.
That doesn't...
I guess this doesn't count as a block that is powered?
I tried to be cute with it.
I have to...
I have to really get back into the whole redstone thingy here.
I am rusty as hell.
Parader needs to go...
here.
What's the best way of doing this, then?
Can I use two torches?
Can I use a torch here?
That sounds illegal.
Doesn't it?
Sounds like it should be outlawed.
I don't have room to get back.
But I guess I can just put this here.
And a shaft in between.
Oh, that's a much way...
I didn't need repeaters.
I just done this.
What am I doing, bro?
Okay.
Let me just see.
So, it's not spinning.
I'm upstairs.
And I go...
I want to go down.
Like that.
Okay.
We're going down.
Now.
Now I'm down.
Ah, but wait.
Holy fuck.
Wait a minute.
This is actually getting a little complicated.
We also need to figure out a way for it to stop when we're down.
So, when we're down.
Like it goes...
Now we're at the bottom.
It needs to automatically stop.
But I guess we can do that when the signal...
Off.
Let me think.
When this is exceeding.
I think we may need to put this closer.
Yeah.
There we go.
Okay.
So, now.
I guess I could just time it.
As soon as I hit the bottom.
I click the switch immediately.
Right?
Okay.
Let me do a dry run.
I'm upstairs.
La la la la la.
It's me.
I'm cooking food.
And I'm going...
Oh!
I want to go down to my basement.
Boing.
It's turning that way.
And now I'm going all the way down.
I'm getting ready.
I see the switch.
It's coming.
I see it.
It's right in front of me.
And I go...
Boop.
And now I want to go back up.
Ah!
But it's still going down.
Shit.
Right.
That's the problem.
It's still going down.
So, we need to revert it, of course.
We're almost there.
So, when I put power to this, overwrite this, it needs to put power to this.
Ah!
Wait a minute.
Maybe...
Oh!
Hold up!
I think I may need to reverse these.
The stop needs to happen before the reverse.
And...
Wait.
Air shift.
Here.
But now I don't know if it's set up correctly.
Let me just see.
So, I need to think about this logically.
I...
It is currently unpowered.
Both of them.
This is steady state.
It's off.
Because...
Yeah.
It doesn't even rotate now.
Right?
So, I go down.
Turning left.
I reach the bottom.
As soon as I reach the bottom, I click.
It stops.
Oh, no.
Yeah.
It doesn't change anything.
Basically, I need this one to be on while this one is off.
At the bottom.
So, we really actually need to revert it again.
But there's an easier way to do this, obviously.
It's just to do...
That.
Ah, but then this is off.
Because this is stronger.
Maybe this needs to be further away.
Ah, but it's spinning the other way.
But now I go like that.
Right, but then this is still on.
So, it's still off here.
Crap.
So, when I click this, this needs to go off.
Maybe this needs to be further away.
I also forgot about the different modes about this.
There's definitely something going on there.
Let me see now.
Okay.
So, it's spinning right now.
I'm at the top, right?
But now the problem is...
Oh, wait a sec.
I need this to affect this, of course, still.
Maybe it is a double inversion.
If we double invert...
Do we have room for that?
If this goes into...
We may need to separate these even more.
Here, shift here.
Okay.
Ah, but now we don't have room.
Damn it!
Get out of the way, tree!
Why you gotta be in the way like that, huh?
Block.
Here.
And now, here.
Into there.
Into.
Block.
I don't have more torches!
Torch alert!
I just had a slight horizontal medicine.
Ha ha ha!
Ohoy!
It was a mini one.
There.
So now!
Get ready.
It's not gonna work, but just get ready anyway.
Ah, wait.
Maybe this is on by...
Wait, hold on a minute.
Put this back to where it was.
No, this needs to be further away, right?
Why is that not...
Wait, I forgot to use the...
Oh, right.
It doesn't work like that.
Ah, I don't have room!
Oh my god.
Move this over.
I can't believe it.
And I'm running out of space down here!
My path I made!
We're gonna have to reinstate the non-path path!
Fuck!
In you go.
Connect it like that.
Make a redstone line.
Now clap your hands.
Ram your feet.
Do the dance.
This goes this way now.
Why?
Because I said so.
In.
No, it needs to be over here.
There.
This goes there.
It still doesn't work!
Here, here.
There we go!
We made it!
And now...
Put it there.
Let me think.
Activate.
It stopped.
State to state.
Down.
Shit!
Here.
Why the...
Oh, wait!
I'm an idiot.
We're not even done here.
Wait, I'm lacking...
What the fuck am I doing?
There.
And there.
Okay, so now...
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Steady state!
Down!
That's right!
We're at the bottom.
We time it.
And...
Boom!
Shit balls!
Ah!
I know why!
It's because this needs to be further away!
Like that!
It's still turning right, dammit!
Why is this not activating?
Oh, maybe because it needs to be...
Steady state.
We go down.
But now this should overwrite that, because it's stronger.
But it's not doing that.
Why is that?
Wait a sec!
Am I overthinking this?
And this is off.
Wait a minute.
Also, this is...
We're inverting twice.
It doesn't even make any sense.
This is doing the same thing.
It's not going to work, because this is stronger.
What does this mode even do, when it's...
Oh!
Hold on!
Turn to left.
No, it's...
I think I'm...
I'm swimming, guys.
I'm out in the ocean right now.
I don't have a boat or a life vest.
It's...
It's deep.
It is.
I ain't got no paddles.
I fucking forgot how these comparators work.
I'm pretty sure when this is on, it overrides that, because it's stronger, right?
But what is the difference when I...
I forgot the difference between that.
Besides, what if we just say we don't care about a comparator?
Let's try and keep it really simple.
So right now, steady state.
We go down.
All we need to do is reverse this fucking direction.
And make it stop spinning.
Or...
Or we make it, uh...
Spin so that we reach the floor.
And then we just simply ignore the fact that...
It still spins, because it physically can't go any further down.
Maybe we just live with that.
The problem is, at the very top...
It's gonna keep going all the way to the top, which is bad.
We want it to stop at a specific point.
I guess I can force that.
Maybe by putting in a block or something.
Some kind of blocker.
Something to say...
No, you can't progress.
Hmm.
Well, that's not clean.
That's bad.
Uh...
I don't know if I want to do that.
How would that even work?
Would I have to put in, like, a little...
Maybe a flapjack or something to stop?
And then I open and close it?
Just in time, I come up and I...
Really close...
Or really fast, I hit the flapjack, you know?
And then we watch it flap around.
So wait a minute.
Get rid of this.
Not that it matters.
Yeah, let's just pretend we don't need this.
Let's try to...
Let's actually reduce this to simple things first.
I tried to do too much at one time.
Keep it super simple.
Let's just not worry about stopping it for now.
Uh...
Let's not do that.
So here's the signal.
Right?
I'm upstairs.
And let's say it is in a steady state right now.
Because it's spinning in the direction where it's pulling up.
But it can't go further up.
Now we're going down.
And...
We're going down.
And it's going to keep going down until it can't go down any further.
Right?
Now we need another switch.
Something to override this.
And that is the comparator.
That is the comparator.
In fact, let's not put it there.
Because otherwise we're not going to be able to compare shit.
We start like this.
It's steady state top.
We go down.
Now we're at the bottom.
That works.
The problem with this is...
It's going to keep spinning.
Which is very unsatisfactory for me.
You know?
And...
I would love for it to just...
I guess we can do a quick test.
Let's say it were to put in a flapjack.
Um...
How about wait a second.
How is that even going to...
Work.
Oh shit!
It's technically part of it.
Oh no.
We can't have that.
Oh!
Then we can't do it.
It's going to be simulated.
Can we not some...
Hold on.
Maybe with the wrench we can do something funny.
Can we somehow...
Can we somehow lock it in this position?
Huh.
I mean, I could just time it.
No, I can't!
That's the thing!
I need to stop it up top.
Maybe I just have a...
You know what?
We could also make it super simple.
We could have another switch.
Oh!
Wait a minute!
I have an idea.
Oh!
This actually...
Our good friend the observer!
When it comes up here, it observes the block in front of it.
Activates a signal on the clutch.
What do you think about that?
And then we would have to install an observer.
Which is also not very nice.
Hmm.
Yeah.
D-d-d-d-d-d.
Either that, or I...
Or I have some kind of switch that when it reaches the top...
Instead of observing it, we just complete a connection to a clutch.
You know?
Oh!
Wait a minute!
So when it comes up to here...
Okay.
Oh!
Wait!
Wait, wait.
I have an idea.
What if we engage the clutch...
Let's see the clutch is like there.
Oh, but yeah.
The clutch needs to be up there.
In that case.
Then it can't be at the floor.
Ah, man.
You know what I could do?
It's really dumb.
But...
This is part of the modern design.
The modern design demands something like this.
That's the modern design.
See?
Can't go up.
It can go down.
But it can't go up.
Wait.
Hey!
Maybe it...
Hmm.
I mean...
That is...
That is a solution to it.
Oh!
We can make it look nice, I guess.
We can use some...
construction.
And you know what?
This is wood.
I would argue it belongs in here.
That's ugly.
Yikes.
And you know what?
It looks kind of cool.
Doesn't it?
Does it even work?
It does work.
Goes down.
Hey, okay.
I mean...
It works.
You know what?
I'm gonna go with it.
We have a...
We're gonna fine-tune this later.
There's gotta be a way to automatically engage the clutch at the right moment, I guess.
Actually, yeah.
We just have a switch at the bottom.
As soon as it slots into place, activates the redstone signal that activates a clutch in the circuit.
Wait.
I'm totally overthinking this.
This is totally how to do it.
Actually, I just figured it out.
Dude!
When you get up here, right?
We just simply have some kind of connection.
Maybe we do it down below, even.
Where it...
Let's say there's a redstone line going like this.
But then it comes up.
Connection engaged.
Activates the clutch right before the motor.
You know?
Same thing at the bottom.
It comes down.
And then we switch it into place like this.
Like that.
It activates.
It goes to the same clutch.
Easy.
Ah, but hold on.
There's an issue with that.
There's an issue with that one.
Because...
If it's slotted in and the connection is made, then it's stuck there.
No matter the toggle on the lever.
So what we would need to do, instead of having it automatically slot in, when we get to the bottom, we simply hit another lever that engages a brake on it.
You know?
It's like engaging the brakes.
Which I guess is kind of satisfying to do.
Yeah.
There it is.
Figured it out.
Boom.
Hell yeah.
We have done it.
I got it all figured out.
Yep.
Let's engage it.
Let's make it happen.
The question is now, how do we make this elegant in here?
This is going to be the fun part.
You know?
This is the stuff I love doing.
It's like having a problem where, okay, we need to, you know, connect this to the thingies and it needs to look good.
That's what I enjoy doing so much.
So, first we have...
Where's my thingy?
Where did I put it?
Not the gear shift.
Ropoli!
Just one.
Put this back here.
Oh, wait a minute.
I need to engage this, I think.
There we go.
Wonderful.
Now we can put this anywhere we want.
Let's say over here for now.
Actually, no.
We don't need this anymore because we're doing the automatic thing.
Let's say I want to bring it from here.
That's kind of elegant, I guess.
Yo, we can even...
Oh, yo.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Even better.
We...
Yeah!
Oh, that's actually so sick.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, nice.
Look how good that looks.
And then we're going to have this go along, but with casings.
Huh?
Ah, but that's going to clash with the wooden style.
Do we care about that?
Maybe we don't care.
It's probably fine.
In fact, I want to rotate this.
There we go.
The question is, can I put rods when there's flapjacks?
I can't!
Oh, shit.
But then we're going to have to see the dirt.
I don't like that either.
No, we don't.
You know why?
Reasons.
There.
We're about to case the shit out of this joint.
Where are they?
Where are my dragons?
No, actually, where are they?
Oh.
Here.
Yeah, we're going to have to cover that up, too.
It's not looking great!
We can fix it in post.
Right now, it's okay.
Don't worry about it.
It's going to come in here.
Ah-ha!
Put a rod.
Put this.
Ha-ha!
Wait, why do I have infinite andesite casings?
Wait, what?
Is this a bug?
Look at this.
I have two andesite casings.
I still have two.
That looks like a bug to me.
Weird.
Now I'm going to use a...
gear shift.
No, I need a, um...
gear box.
And I don't even need a vertical one.
The rare horizontal gear box...
comes in clutch right now.
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
Here.
Z-z.
Another one is needed.
Damn.
I need cocks.
I don't have any.
Wood?
Okay, I need wood.
One, two, three, four.
Nice.
Are you ready?
Here we go!
Boink.
Oh, look at the rotation on this.
Oh, oh, no.
See ya!
Bye-bye!
Ha-ha-ha!
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
Look at that!
That's wonderful.
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
Hold on.
Now we need a clutch?
No, what was it?
Gearshift?
There.
The question is, how do we redstone the crap out of that?
That's kind of awkward.
I know how.
Tell me that isn't amazing!
It's gonna stop here.
Look.
Yeah!
All right!
Eh-eh- Okay, that actually works pretty well, I guess.
Maybe we don't need to clutch that.
This-this is already kinda elegant.
It's not even spinning or anything.
It's kinda nice.
Not bad!
Now, let's say we're downstairs.
This is where it gets a little eww, you know?
Now we gotta wire it up to a switch down there, and that's-that wiring needs to go all the way up here, and it's gonna be great.
Hmm.
Yeah.
I'm sure that's gonna be easy.
Redstone dust.
Um.
Whoa!
Lasers!
That's it?
Dude, it's actually the laser!
Holy crap!
Laser time!
Laser!
We need a receiver!
No?
Oh, what was it called?
Uh, something about-
Uh, receptacle...
Uh...
Nope.
What the fuck was it called?
I'm gonna find it.
But, uh, amethyst shard, andesite casing, I got it.
Andesite shard is down here.
I got two andesite casings, I think.
Don't I?
Didn't I just have two of them?
Okay, calm down.
Where...
is it?
Did I use them just now?
What did I use them on?
I was outside, I had two on me.
I demonst- Oh, I used them to make the gear, uh, boxes.
That's right.
True.
Do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do.
Now we need- Andesite!
Aloys!
Beep-beep-beep-beep-beep-beep.
Laser!
Laserpointer!
Yeah, I don't need to ponder on that.
I know how it works.
Bitch!
No, I'm sorry.
Uh, we need the receiver.
It was called something like a receiver.
We'll find it.
That one.
Nope, not that one.
It's here somewhere.
Show me the goods.
It's gonna look sci-fi.
It's easy to see.
Oh, no.
Maybe I didn't discover it yet.
I did definitely in the first world.
Laserpointer.
Optical sensor.
That's it.
I think.
Electron tube.
Amethyst shard.
Man, do I even have the tube anymore?
Oops.
We need to make more quartz.
My inventory is starting to become disgusting again.
Nobody likes a disgusting inventory.
Am I right?
I'm right.
Looking good.
Now we gotta...
We gotta rub it.
Are we gonna tube it?
What's this?
Nixie tube.
Not happening now.
There we go.
Optical sensor.
Boom.
Okay, maybe I will ponder on that.
Let's see.
Optical sensors can detect blocks which obstruct its laser pointer?
Oh.
Okay.
Oh, okay.
Okay, I see.
I see.
When a block is detected, a redstone signal is emitted.
Dude, can I make like a mirror?
Just like National Treasure with the one true god.
I wanna mirror this laser around all kinds of places.
The optical sensor's signal strength is relative to its detected block's distance.
Distance.
Okay.
I see.
The maximum distance can be configured using the value panel.
Fancy.
When a filter is applied...
Wait, it only shows the iron stuff in the way?
Only matching blocks will emit a signal.
Oh.
Oh, that's interesting.
But it still blocks the signal, though.
It seems.
Okay, let me see the laser.
Okay.
Laser pointers emit a laser.
Yes.
I get it.
It can be obstructed by blocks.
Laser sensors can detect the laser when unobstructed.
Yes.
They will emit a signal dependent on the laser power.
When a filter is applied.
Right-clicking the front or back face with a wrench inverts redstone power.
The maxed casting distance can be adjusted on the back.
Okay, okay.
I get it.
I think.
The question is, can I do it vertically?
Oh, I must be able to.
Oh, yeah.
Definitely.
Big beam.
Sick.
So, basically...
Wait a minute.
Oh, no.
Ah.
Bye.
If I...
Let me try and see if I can do this really nicely.
Wait, I can even put the laser...
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Ideas are forming.
Let's say I put the laser on the contraption.
Right?
No.
I think there's an idea there.
You know, the further down it goes, the longer the laser has to travel.
Something like that.
There's definitely an idea there.
But I could put it something like here.
Or even, actually, maybe next to it.
But, no.
This is fine for now.
I'm going to put it there.
Let's say I do that.
And it somehow turns on that laser, right?
And then it's at the very bottom.
At the very bottom, we have an optical...
Thingamajig.
And we can somehow switch that off and on, I guess.
To receive the laser.
Let's try it, man.
And you know what?
I...
No, I'm not going to trust blindly here.
But I will do this.
Nearsighted.
Nice.
Let me see if I can connect these real quick.
Temporary ugliness coming up.
Oh, no.
Stop flapping.
Ah, it doesn't work like that, right?
Okay.
Too bad.
What's an easy way to do this?
Something fast.
Something that works real quick.
Can I somehow connect that?
I guess I can...
Oh, wait.
I have an idea.
Ah, but the switch is going to override.
Mmm.
Right.
I think I'm trying to solve it a little too much at the same time here.
It ain't good.
It also doesn't look nice to have a laser just shooting up, you know?
It's a little jank.
For sure.
Anyway.
I gotta call it there.
Because I gotta go.
I really gotta go.
Short stream today.
So, yeah.
I'll have to think about that one.
But what do you guys think?
The elevator is finally there!
Something I've been wanting to do since day one of Minecraft.
We finally have it!
So amazing!
Turn that off.
It's actually so goddamn cool that you can do this and create.
When I read you saying, when are you planning to start physics stuff?
I was thinking of the...
When do we plan to start?
At some point, we're gonna do that.
I mean, this is already that, isn't it?
But yeah, we're gonna get into it later.
This is a long series, guys.
I can tell you already.
This mod is deep, okay?
This needs to cook for a while.
It needs to simmer before the food is done.
And you know what?
It's gonna feel good to cook it.
The smells in the kitchen are delicious, you know?
We're simmering.
We're not in any hurry here.
I'm enjoying this so much, you know?
I don't wanna hurry it at all.
I'm gonna extract every bit of enjoyment I can out of this.
Can you say hi to Nixu, Denmark's almost best gamer?
Hi, Nixu.
Denmark's almost best gamer.
Do a cardboard stream next time to compensate?
Are you saying I've been a little too technical this time around?
I know not a lot of people enjoy watching the Redstone stuff, but I really do enjoy fiddling with it, you know?
I like just having fun with it and trying to mess around with it and...
make things work.
It's fun.
I may not be the best or the fastest or the brightest on that, but I'm having fun.
And that's all that matters.
Yeah, it's a very technical mod.
I'm already getting that feeling, you know?
Some of those components you can have...
Man, it almost breaks my brain already, you know?
Trying to imagine all the different things you can possibly do now.
Make the double slit experiment with lasers in Minecraft?
I doubt they're gonna have that simulated.
But who knows?
It would be a fun thing if they actually had that as an easter egg and create, you know?
If you put a...
Like a mirror.
Or not a mirror, a slit.
And then you put a laser in between and it actually does something like that.
And then when you put an observer in between, right?
That's when it happens.
The actual observer block.
It's almost too perfect.
That easter egg writes itself.
That would be so cool.
Okay, guys.
I'm out of here.
This was a quick stream.
I just wanted to get some fast Minecraft in.
I'm gonna...
Get back to packing up my stuff.
And yeah.
I'll see you around.
There's more Minecraft this week before I start moving for sure.
The computer and...
You know, my table and all that is the last thing I move.
So I'll be able to stream until the very end.
Yeah.
I'll see you around.
Bye-bye.